# UTTAM KUMAR

Melbourne, Australia, AU 0470228392 uttam12061988@gmail.com



## Senior UI Developer at Capgemini

#### Summary

I have 3+ years of experience on designing and implementing modular extensible UI, Integrated responsive UI designs into frameworks for web and mobile using HTML5, CSS3 and jQuery / JavaScript. I was participated on Building CRM application in a open source platform. Familiar with Agile methodology

### Work History -

May 2015 - Present Senior UI Designer

Capgemini Australia

Successfully established and built software for client Powercor.I am contributerd in this project as a FrontEnd Developer where i integrate PSD to HTMl and converted the HTMLs to functional Visualforce pages in angularjs.

Jun 2014 - May 2015 UX/UI Developer

Ilantus Technologies Pvt. Ltd

This an Product based company who masters in Identity and Access management. Here i built a clean mobile supported designs using bootstrap and communicated with back end with restful web services using REST. js and Javascript Ajax

Jun 2012 - May 2014 Front End Developer

14infotech Pvt. Ltd.

This is my first company which was correlated with affordableseo in miami, where i got a chance to build wordpress themes for around 30 to 40 web sites and i got a good exposure on Javascript and jquery, using these skills i built a framework to support single page applications.

#### Education

2012 Master in Computer Application

Orissa Computer Academy

Web Designs

To convert Mockups to standard web pages i used below skills

HTML5,CSS3,Bootstrap

Freamworks

Wordpress,PHP,Magento,Salesforce,Mysql,Nodejs,Java

Scripts

Javascript

Jquery, Jquery UI, Jquery Mobile UI(Frontend Validation, Styling)

Jquery Validator

Ajax,Json,Rest.js(Web Services)

Mustache, handlebars (Templating)

Angularjs(SPA)

Nodejs(ServerSide)

## **Personal Information**

Father: Rapeti Kanaka Rao Date of birth: 12th june 1988

Passport: J8489940
Pancard: BHXPR5873D

Location: 305,268 Flinders Street, Melbourne, VIC - 3000

Languages: Telugu, Oriya, Hindi and English